# MATTHEWIKANE





Cape Town/Stellenbosch | SA/UK Citizen |

082 219 7838

mattkane94@gmail.com

### PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a capable, determined and inquisitive individual with a strong finance and investment management background and a keen interest in data and analytics. My education and work experience have developed in me a strong analytical ability and the capacity to apply logic and critical thinking to tasks and problems at hand. I am people-oriented, easy-going and adaptable, and enjoy working in a team environment. I am first and foremost interested in learning and building my career. Beyond work, I am passionate about nature, outdoor activities and particularly endurance sports.

#### KEY ATTRIBUTES

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Analytical and attention to detail Strong logic and problem-solving ability Effective communicator

SOL Financial analysis **DBMS** Python, Java

MS Excel HTML, CSS, JavaScript

## EDUCATION

**Software Engineering Bootcamp** 

Feb, 2022 - Aug, 2022

HyperionDev, Cape Town

2nd student in class (99% average)

**BCom Honours (Investment Management, Financial Management)** 

2014 - 2017

Stellenbosch University, Stellenbosch

BCom Investment Management degree and BCom Honours (Financial Management)

Final Honours year average: 74%

**CFA Level 1** Dec, 2017

**CFA Institute, Global** 

2008 - 2012 **High School** 

Rondebosch Boys' High School, Cape Town

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Finance Intern Feb, 2021 - Oct, 2021

#### FVC Advisors Hedge Fund - Cape Town, SA

- Daily fund performance reporting
- Fundamental international equity/company analysis
- Compilation of portfolio Net Asset Value

## Scientific English Editor

March, 2018 - Present

## MDPI AG - Basel, Switzerland (Remote)

- Technical & language editing of research transcripts published across various academic journals
- Intensively detail-oriented role
- Requires high-level proficiency in English language and scientific writing

## References are available upon request